Tan Yin Lin 陈颖宁

WRITER / JOURNALIST

SINGAPORE (AVAILABLE FOR RELOCATION AND REMOTE WORK)

PROFILE —

- Journalism. Passion for understanding the world through journalism. Curious about current affairs and particularly interested in issues related to East Asia. Adaptable, resourceful, and adept at establishing contacts by building trust and relationships with others. A team player who thrives in high-pressure environments and delivers well-written copies under tight deadlines.
- Research. Research experience in academia and journalism. Engaged
 essential skills such as data analysis and interpretation, fact-checking,
 proof-reading, transcription, translation, and conducting interviews. Persistent
 and adaptable in the face of research obstacles. Committed to conducting
 rigorous research to produce honest reporting and thoughtful analysis.

EXPERIENCE ---

RICE Media

MAY 2020 - JUL 2020

Editorial Intern

Report and write features, op-eds, and commentaries with a focus on culture and current affairs. Pitch story ideas, craft angles for breaking news, and create branded content for clients. Collaborate with editors, designers, and producers to produce insightful articles. Full list of bylines at https://www.ricemedia.co/author/tan-yin-lin/.

Atlas Obscura, TripZilla, etc.

Freelance Writer

Pitch original story ideas to digital media publications. Handle the entire journalistic process, from crafting angles to sourcing for contacts, doing research and fieldwork, and taking photos. Full portfolio at https://tylanin.github.io/writing/.

National University of Singapore

MAY 2018 - MAY 2020

NOV 2016 - PRESENT

Research Assistant

Held multiple part-time positions with the Psychology and English Language Departments. Conducted research, facilitated experiments, and analysed data.

L'Oreal NOV 2015

Digital Media Intern

Drafted social media calendar for Garnier Singapore. Wrote product copies for L'Oreal's online store. Part of the English Language Elective Scholarship (ELES) programme.

EDUCATION -

National University of Singapore

JUL 2016 - JUL 2020

B.A. Honours (1st Class) in English Language + University Scholars Programme Attained CAP of 4.59. Coursework in linguistics, philosophy, writing, statistics, and psychology. Member of Dance Blast! and D'Hoppers Dance Crew. Participated in my college's road relay, live music, and Pecha Kucha (storytelling, but snappy) clubs.

http://tvlanin.github.io

+65 9783 9096 tylanin@gmail.com

PROJECTS ---

2020 · INTER.TXT, Writer/Editor 2020 · 134wpm, Writer/Editor 2019 · XDS Data Storytelling Competition, 4th Place

SKILLS -

Writing · Reporting · Editing · Research · Data Interpretation · English-Mandarin Translation · Transcription · Interviewing · Photography · Web Design

LANGUAGES ---

Native: English, Mandarin Chinese Basic: Korean, Japanese, French Receptive: Hokkien, Teochew

SOFTWARE -

HTML · CSS · Photoshop · Premiere
Pro · Illustrator · Microsoft Suite ·
Audacity · Audition · ELAN · PRAAT

AWARDS ----

2018 · USP Senior Honour Roll
2017 · Faculty of Arts and Sciences
Special Book Prize (Top Student)
2017 · USP Honour Roll
2015 · English Language Elective
Scholarship (ELES)